Guide to the Ron Bluestein papers, circa 1982-1987.
Bluestein, Ron papers
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Ron Bluestein papers, circa 1982-1987.
7749
Ron Bluestein
2.2 cubic feet.
Photographs, journal.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Collected journals and photographs of writer Ron Bluestein.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Ron Bluestein was born in Philadelphia on February 4, 1949 and died from cancer on September 20, 2007 in his sister's home in Springfield, PA. His journal writing, started as an assignment in Arthur Lessing's philosophy class at Lake Forrest College, Illinois in 1969, continued avidly across the years. Bluestein wrote about AIDS hospice, art, entertainment, spirituality, and sex clubs for the Bay Area Reporter, the Advocate, Vogue, and other publications. In about 1984 he helped start the San Francisco Jacks, a safe sex group still active in 2007 and described as "a fellowship of men who like to jack-off in the company of like-minded men." He supported himself as a waiter and as a caretaker in a San Francisco Zen center. He was close with his sister Sheryl Bluestein McShea who added his nickname Ronnette as her middle name after his death.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
The collection contains albums with photographs Bluestein took of nude men, some taken in his apartment, some taken at clubs. Additionally, all of the journals he kept during his lifetime, approximately 60 volumes dating from 1968 until 2006. A small number of audiocassette recordings of various interviews.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Bluestein, Ron
Subjects:
Gay men--Sexual behavior.
Form and Genre Terms:
Erotica.; Photographs.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
Access Restrictions:
Photograph albums and photographs in boxes 2 and 3 may not be viewed until 2038.
RELATED MATERIALS
Collecting program: Human Sexuality Collection.
CONTAINER LIST
- Re-evaluation Counseling material (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Published pornography and photographs by Mark I. Chester, 1 volume (Box 1)
- Unpublished photographs by Mark I. Chester (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Photograph by Rikki Ercoli of Dan Martin (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Memorial Service and Acknowledgements, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Poetry (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Published Writing, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Orpheus Concert Program and DVD-R (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Poetry and Sketches, 1 volume (Box 1)
- "Ronnie's Last Entry" by Sheryl Ronette McShea, 2010; 1 volume (Box 4)
  Note from Sheryl McShea: "Read me first, even if it's the last entry." Signed.
- Journals, 1968-1989; 23 volumes (Box 4, Folder 2-24)
- Journals, 1989-1997; 19 volumes (Box 5, Folder 1-19)
- Journals, 1998-2004; 16 volumes (Box 6, Folder 1-16)
- Journals, 2004-2006; 4 volume (Box 7, Folder 1-4)
- "Flowers of Asphalt," photograph album of individuals [RESTRICTED], 12 volumes (Box 2)
- Photograph albums of individuals [RESTRICTED], 5 volumes (Box 2)
- Photograph albums of individuals [RESTRICTED], 7 volumes (Box 3)
- Exo-Ero Ball and photographs of individuals [RESTRICTED], 1982, 1984, 1986; 3 volumes (Box 3)
- Exo-Ero Ball [RESTRICTED], 1985-1987, undated; 5 volumes (Box 3)
- Photographs of individuals, groups and events [RESTRICTED] (Box 3, Folder 1-2)
- Audiocassettes 1-4: Interview with Richard Gac (Box 8)
- Audiocassette 5: Interview at Zen Center Hospice (Box 8)
- Audiocassette 6: Interview with Ron Henderson, Volunteer at Shante (AIDS Hospital-Hospice) (Box 8)
- Audiocassette 7: Interview with Randy Harrey (Shante Tape) (Box 8)
- Audiocassette 8: Interview with Andre Welton (Box 8)
- Audiocassette 9: Interview with Anne Rice (Box 8)
- Audiocassette 10: Interview with Lia Zeni Gutero, 1985 (Box 8)
- Audiocassette 11: Interview with Art Montenegro, 1989 (Box 8)
- Audiocassette 12: Recording of Bluestein Singing to His Grandmother (Box 8)